hello and welcome to the ninth tutorial
on how to program gript 2 and the last
tutorial I taught you about temp
variables and this do variables in this
tutorial I'm going to teach you about
two two new variables the client
variable and the client R variable so
let's open level editor and let's start
typing
player. client
do yellow is equal to
10 or we can make it equal
to
hello
hello so basically a client variable is
a variable that I saved on the
player this
variable will work it can be created on
any MPC and can be edited server side or
client side and any MP PC will be able
to use it because it's on the player not
on the NPC but just on the player him or
herself so let's close this and save it
and
run if you go to RC and click the player
list you can look at the player list and
rightclick myself and go to script Flags
there should be a variable called
client. hello I mean client. yellow is
equal to hello can close that lower
this
if there now there's a next variable
it's called a client R variable client R
variables are essentially the same as
client variables except you cannot
create them or change them on client
side they will only they can you can
only create or change them on server
side however they can be used on client
side
so I'll show you that in a
second so
oh the thing is with centar variables is
that you can't create them with an
oncreated function you can only create
them with something else like
player enters I'm not too sure why but
just know you can't create them with
oncreated so let's save
that and let's say hi I'll say hello now
I'm typing hi but when I enter it it
says hello because it's instantly
changing my chat to say
hello so that concludes this
tutorial and oh and I just want to
mention that whenever you're using these
kind of variables
or in when you're using client side you
can take out the player
dot but on server side you have to have
the player dot in the beginning the
reason of this is because on client side
it client side only affects you so it
knows who to whose variable to use but
on server side it affects all the
players in the level so it doesn't know
who client. yellow to find who what
player to locate and change their or use
their client r. yellow variable so this
shows that it's targeting us us as the
player and changing the client are that
yellow variable to hello so anyway that
concludes this
tutorial and I'll probably be teaching
another two or one variables in next
tutorial so